MATJAŽ LOVENJAK

IT ENGINEER



PROFILE

Experienced Information Technology Engineer with a background in the manufacturing industry. Recently transitioned into web development, focusing on front-end technologies. Passionate about creating modern and user-friendly web solutions and excited to contribute my skills as a web developer.



17.8.1988



Kregarjeva 11, 8250 Brežice



+386 41 741 925



matjaz.lovenjak@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/matjaz-lovenjak



https://github.com/rubuz

EDUCATION

IT Engineer

Šolski center Novo mesto, Short-cycle Higher Vocational College, IT engineering

2013 - 2016

SKILLS

WINDOWS OS IT HARDWARE

UX/UI HTML, CSS, JS

WORDPRESS TROUBLESHOOT

TEAMWORK COMMUNICATION

REACT JS GIT

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer / System Administrator Adria Mobil d.o.o., Novo mesto

2023 - present

Web Developer with a background in system administration and user support, specializing in digitalizing processes and developing web applications. Committed to streamlining operations, improving efficiency, and driving organizational growth through process digitalization. Job roles and responsibilities are:

- analyze existing processes and identify opportunities for digitalization;
- creating user-friendly interfaces and intuitive navigation for efficient process execution;
- integrating data sources and APIs to enable seamless information flow and enhance process automation;
- developing web applications to automate manual workflows and streamline operations;

System administrator

2017 - 2023

Adria Mobil d.o.o., Novo mesto

Working in an IT department mainly as an endpoint administrator and user support. Frequently interacting with end users in a multi-user organization, where I developed problem solving and communication skills. My job roles and responsibilities are:

- · providing dedicated technical support to individual users;
- maintaining records of IT assets, planning for future IT investments and upgrades;
- managing, troubleshooting, licensing, and updating hardware and software assets. Then, documenting these activities and following a strategic approach, per organizational policy;
- monitoring system health;
- troubleshooting and fixing issues that compromise system performance or access to an IT service:
- writing Powershell scripts to automate certain IT processes;
- testing software and hardware;
- conducting training programs to bring users up to pace with new software installations or IT system changes.

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- Tech: I enjoy keeping myself updated with the latest consumer tech
- Motorcycles: I like working on my motorcycle and going on trips with it
- Fitness: I enjoy working out at my local gym to stay fit and healthy
- Coffee: I excel at making coffee with different brewing methods
- Gaming: having been a passionate gamer my whole life, I love all kinds of games (PC, console, board)